<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://aieslab.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://aieslab.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-11-27T18:06:09+00:00</updated><id>https://aieslab.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Autonomous &amp;amp; Intelligent Energy Systems Lab</title><subtitle>The Autonomous and Intelligent Energy Systems Lab (AIES) studies how advanced control methods and AI can improve energy efficiency and operational performance in real systems. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Launching the AIES Lab</title><link href="https://aieslab.github.io/blog/2024/lab-launch/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Launching the AIES Lab"/><published>2024-11-01T10:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-11-01T10:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://aieslab.github.io/blog/2024/lab-launch</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://aieslab.github.io/blog/2024/lab-launch/"><![CDATA[<p>We’re excited to announce the launch of the Autonomous and Intelligent Energy Systems Lab! Our mission is to develop advanced control and AI methods that make energy systems more efficient, sustainable, and reliable.</p> <h2 id="our-focus">Our Focus</h2> <p>The lab focuses on three key areas:</p> <ol> <li><strong>HVAC and Industrial Cooling</strong> - Developing model predictive control and reinforcement learning approaches for building systems</li> <li><strong>Data Center Optimization</strong> - Improving energy efficiency in data center cooling and operations</li> <li><strong>Semantic Modelling</strong> - Creating structured representations that enable automated control deployment</li> </ol> <h2 id="what-makes-us-different">What Makes Us Different</h2> <p>We’re committed to bridging the gap between research and practice. Every method we develop is designed with real-world deployment in mind, tested on actual equipment, and validated with industry partners.</p> <h2 id="get-involved">Get Involved</h2> <p>If you’re interested in working with us, check out our <a href="/join/">Join</a> page for opportunities.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing the Autonomous and Intelligent Energy Systems Lab]]></summary></entry></feed>